ABOUT ME

I'm a passionate and enthusiastic developer with experience in full-stack development. I have a wide range of experience starting from designing and building small web sites to architect scale real-time web and mobile apps. I continue improving my Javascript stack, with Reactjs, React Native, and Node.js. I try to expand in my area of expertise every day and I'm not afraid to learn new things.

CONTACT



+55 92 98418-2160



jilvan.silva@gmail.com



@jilvanx github.com/jilvanx



https://jilvanx.github.io

SKILLS

React

React Native

Node.js

PHP

Java

Angular 2+

Jest

Cypress

Docker

RabbitMQ

Apache Kafka

Git

JILVAN CÂNDIDO DA SILVA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Developer - Invillia

since May 2019

Developing and maintaining products for clients using Next.js (React) in the frontend and Node.js in the backend. Scrum for agile project management methodology and GitHub for version control.

Tech Leader - ICTS - Institute of Technology

since December 2019 - April 2020

Responsible for monitoring activities and delivering the energy efficiency project that makes up a real-time monitoring solution using IoT. Participation in the architecture and definition of technologies used in the project such as Node.js, React.js, React Native, Kafka, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Redis, Docker and Jest for tests. For DevOps activities I used Google Cloud Platform to host containers.

Full Stack Developer - FIT - Institute of Technology

since March 2018 - November 2019

I worked to develop and maintain microservices that collect data from other areas such as production factory, stock, and financial to process and group the information to show on a dashboard for management decisions. To containers, I used docker to build microservices. I used Node.js and Spring Boot (JAVA) on the backend and React.js and React Native on the frontend. For tests, we used Cypress and Jest. Scrum for agile project management methodology, JIRA for issues management, and BitBucket (Git) to version control.

Full Stack Developer - SENAI - AM

since December 2014 - February 2018

I worked as a front-end developer to maintain the companies home page. I made some custom queries on the SQL server to extract data to use on reports, and I used Scrum for agile framework management.

Full Stack Developer - Rádio TV do Amazonas

August 2007 - November 2014

I worked on the migration and maintenance of desktops applications such as financial and commercial to the web application using ASP.NET MVC. I optimized stored procedures and queries on SQL Server. Scrum for agile project management methodology and SVN to version control.

EDUCATION

Node.js, Express, React, React Native, MongoDB and Docker.

Abril 2019

Rocketseat

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

March 2000 - December 2004

UNIP - Brazil